<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-05-06T17:51:01+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Developing This Blog</title><subtitle>This is where I chronicle the journey I take through web development, app  development, desktop development, and self development.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Web Development is for Everyone!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/web/development/2017/05/04/web-development-is-for-everyone.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Web Development is for Everyone!" /><published>2017-05-04T14:55:19+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-04T14:55:19+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/web/development/2017/05/04/web-development-is-for-everyone</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/web/development/2017/05/04/web-development-is-for-everyone.html">&lt;p&gt;I am not sure about you, but I know that I always felt web development was not for me. I envisioned that web developers were very art or graphic driven. I felt that web development depended on the developer being able to lay something out that was more pretty than it was functional. Detrementally to me, I thought that web development lacked any coding skill. I am here to say, whole heartedly, that I was wrong. The coding for a website can be extremely complex.  I am learning this now through my work on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freecodecamp.com&quot;&gt;Free Code Camp&lt;/a&gt; challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I do not want to disparage web developers. I always thought there was talent in it, even when it was graphically driven. What I want to get out of this post is for people to understand that anyone can learn it. You don’t have to be artistically oriented, I know I am not. There are resources to help out people who only know how to code and don’t know anything about UI or UX. One of the biggest helpers for me so far has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://coolors.co&quot;&gt;Coolors&lt;/a&gt;. This will help you coordinate colors on your page. It was a game changer for me. I also want to shoutout the incredible community behind both web development and in general. I have found such great resources through [@CodeNewbies] and all the folks going through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23100DaysOfCode&amp;amp;src=tyah&quot;&gt;#100DaysOfCode&lt;/a&gt; have been very inspiring. I am on day 16 myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first post I have on this blog and I hope there are many more to come. I wanted to use this time to shoutout what I have started learning about web development and the great resources that I have come across for it, so far. Being new on my journey through web development, I have so much more to learn. I hope someone out there will benefit from this as much as I have benefitted from this great community in my short time. The posts to come will start be more code heavy as I learn cool tips and tricks (or even develop some of my own).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I am not sure about you, but I know that I always felt web development was not for me. I envisioned that web developers were very art or graphic driven. I felt that web development depended on the developer being able to lay something out that was more pretty than it was functional. Detrementally to me, I thought that web development lacked any coding skill. I am here to say, whole heartedly, that I was wrong. The coding for a website can be extremely complex. I am learning this now through my work on Free Code Camp challenges.</summary></entry></feed>